boulesse.com 2017-02-08

# Imprint & Privacy Policy - BOULESSE

****Boulesse.com****

****Boulesse GmbH****

Prinz-Eugen-Straße 2/5

1040 Vienna

Austria

Landline: +43 1 512 05 92 (available Monday to Friday from 9AM to 6PM CET)

E-Mail: [office@boulesse.com](mailto:office@boulesse.com)

****Managing Directors:  ****Beatrice and Daniel Tourou

**Legal Form:  **Gesellschaft mit beschraenkter Haftung (GmbH)

**Membership:  **The Austrian Economic Chambers, Federal Department for Trade

**Business Licence:  **Commercial Trade, Reg.ZI.: 111822F01/08 of the Municipal Authority of the City of Vienna

Registered at the Commercial Court of Vienna

Commercial registration no.: FN 403708 p

VAT-ID no.: ATU68242608

DPR no.: 4011134

Nature and purpose of the business: Trading

Place of jurisdiction: Vienna, Austria

Link to the online arbitration platform according to the ODR regulation: <http://ec.europa.eu/consumers/odr/>

**Privacy Policy**

Valid from 7 November 2016  

**1\. INTRODUCTION**

1.1.   The confidentiality, security and protection of personal data of our customers are first priority for Boulesse. Boulesse is therefore committed to a responsible use of your personal data in compliance with all applicable laws in accordance with this privacy policy.

1.2.   This privacy policy of Boulesse determines the terms and conditions subject to which Boulesse processes any personal data. The use of the website www.boulesse.com operated by Boulesse and of the online shop operated at that website (“Boulesse-Webshop”) is solely governed by this privacy policy which is an integral and binding part of the [General Terms and Conditions of Boulesse](https://boulesse.com/terms-conditions). By visiting the Boulesse-Webshop, you agree to this privacy policy.

1.3.   Due to the business model of Boulesse to offer to businesses engaged in the fashion and lifestyle business (“Boutiques”) within the meaning of section 1 of the Austrian Business Enterprise Code (Unternehmensgesetzbuch – UGB) the possibility to use the Boulesse-Webshop as a marketplace platform this privacy policy in particular also applies to the transmission of your personal data to the Boutiques and to the processing of your personal data by the Boutiques.  

**2\. PRINCIPAL**

The principal (Auftraggeber) within the meaning of the Austrian Data Protection Act 2000 (Datenschutzgesetz 2000 – DSG) is Boulesse GmbH, Stubenbastei 12/12, 1010 Vienna, FN 403708p of Commercial Court Vienna (Handelsgericht Wien) (“Boulesse”).

**3\. COLLECTION AND RECORDING OF DATA**

3.1.   In the course of your visit to the Boulesse-Webshop, your orders in the Boulesse-Webshop and your submission of any data to your customer account Boulesse collects the following personal data (“Collected Data”):

a)  Information given by you:

Boulesse collects and records all data, which you enter in the Boulesse-Webshop, or you submit in any other way, for example during any ordering process or to your customer account. This information includes name, gender, residential address, delivery address, e-mail address and the password of your customer account.

b)  Communication by e-mail:

Boulesse collects and records all data, which you transmit to us by e-mail. Furthermore, Boulesse collects and records information about which e-mails from Boulesse you open, provided this function is supported by your device. If you do not want to receive e-mails for advertising purposes or if you generally do not want to receive any e-mails from Boulesse (with the exception of e-mails, which are necessary in connection with the ordering process, such as order confirmations and invoices) please contact us by e-mail to [info@boulesse.com](mailto:info@boulesse.com) with the subject “Unsubscribe”.

c)  Automatic information:

In the course of your visit of the Boulesse-Webshop or if you get in contact with Boulesse in any other way Boulesse receives and records certain information. Boulesse in particular uses cookies (see section 4 below) and remarketing tags as well as tracking pixels (see section 6 below) and receives certain information as soon as your web browser opens the Boulesse-Webshop or advertisement and other content provided by and on behalf of Boulesse on other websites. In particular, the IP-address of your device, the web browser you used and the pages of the Boulesse-Webshop you visited will be collected and recorded in the course of your visit of the Boulesse-Webshop.

d)  Mobile devices

If you download or use applications of Boulesse on your mobile device, activate location-based services and agreed to the transmission of information, you may transmit information regarding your location, the device you use and the unique identification number of your device. On most devices, it is possible to deactivate location-based services.

3.2.   Boulesse will neither collect nor record bank account and credit card data. The bank account and credit card data, which you specify in the course of the ordering process, will be transmitted directly to the bank keeping your account or to the issuer of your credit card or to the authorized service provider, respectively. Boulesse at no point in time will have access to such data.

3.3.   Boulesse under tax and commercial legislation is subject to certain requirements of data recording and storage and therefore is obliged to store Collected Data for at least seven years and in certain cases (judicial or administrative proceedings) for a longer period. This means Collected Data may be stored by Boulesse beyond the time of deletion of your customer account.  

**4\. COOKIES**

4.1.   The Boulesse-Webshop uses cookies. Cookies are small data packages, which are automatically transmitted to your web browser and are stored on your device when you visit a website. Cookies save information about your online preferences and enable Boulesse to fine-tune the design, the technical properties and the product range of the Boulesse-Webshop in order to maximize and continuously improve your shopping experience and your security in the Boulesse-Webshop.

4.2.   You may configure your web browser in a way that either all cookies will be accepted, or you will be notified before the installation of any cookies, or all cookies will be generally declined. You can also manually delete all or selected cookies in your browser options at any time. Please note that in case of deactivation of cookies you may not be able to use certain personalized services of the Boulesse-Webshop.

**5\. DATA PROCESSING**

5.1.   Boulesse processes the Collected Data for the following purposes:

a)  Communication with you

b)  Processing of orders (in particular delivery of goods, handling and return of payments)

c)  Enabling the implementation of technical, logistic or other services on behalf of Boulesse

d)  Improvement of the product range of the Boulesse-Webshop

e)  Personalization of future shopping experiences

f)  Prevention of misuse of the Boulesse-Webshop

g)  Improvement of design and technical properties of the Boulesse-Webshop

h)  For mobile devices: Offering of location-based services, such as search results or other personalized contents

5.2.   In addition, Boulesse processes the Collected Data for its own marketing measures such as the mailing of direct advertising or general information of advertising nature (newsletters). Boulesse for these purposes also transmits your Collected Data (name, gender, residential address and e-mail address) to those Boutiques, the listed goods of which you have ordered or from which you explicitly requested (over your customer account) the receipt of advertisement. Other than by transfer of certain Collected Data according to sections 6 through 9 Boulesse does not transmit any Collected Data to any other person.

5.3.   Upon your request Boulesse will not use your Collected Data for advertising purposes and will not transmit your Collected Data to Boutiques for advertising purposes. If you do not want to receive e-mails for advertising purposes, please contact us by e-mail to [info@boulesse.com](mailto:info@boulesse.com) with the subject “Unsubscribe”  

**6\. CUSTOM AUDIENCE**

6.1.   Boulesse uses the “Custom Audience”-technology for the Boulesse-Webshop. Custom Audience is a service provided by Facebook Inc., 1601 South California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA, and Facebook Ireland Limited, Hanover Reach, 5-7 Hanover Quay, Dublin 2, Ireland, respectively (jointly “Facebook“). The Custom Audience technology is used for statistical purposes and for market research and allows Boulesse to realise the purposes indicated in section 5 and in particular to measure and design more effectively its activities on Facebook, e.g. by showing certain posts or advertisements on Facebook only to visitors of the Boulesse-Webshop.

6.2.   In order to use the Custom Audience technology so-called remarketing tags and tracking pixels are integrated in the Boulesse-Webshop. When you visit the Boulesse-Webshop, a direct connection is established between your browser and the Facebook server by way of the remarketing tag. Through this process, Facebook exclusively receives the IP-address of your device and the information that you have visited the Boulesse-Webshop using that IP-address. This way, Facebook can match your visit in the Boulesse-Webshop to your Facebook account and is able to display targeted posts and ads in your Facebook account. In order to use the Custom Audience technology even more efficiently, Boulesse reserves the right to transmit to Facebook your e-mail address and information, which Boulesse has collected by way of cookies. Apart from your IP-address and your e-mail address Facebook receives no Collected Data from Boulesse by way of the Custom Audience-technology. Further information can be found in Facebook’s data policy at <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>. If you do not want your data to be collected via Custom Audience and your IP-address or your e-mail-address not transmitted to Facebook, you can deactivate Custom Audiences [here](https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/).  

**7\. SOCIAL MEDIA-PLUGINS**

7.1.   Moreover, the Boulesse-Webshop includes certain features of third party providers (so-called plug-ins) of social media platforms (e.g. Facebook, Twitter, Google+). These plug-ins enable visitors of the Boulesse-Webshop to share information over social networks.

7.2.   If you click on an icon in the Boulesse-Webshop, which is linked to such a plug-in (e.g. like-button as used on Facebook) the servers of that third party provider, will be contacted automatically. When such contact is established, certain data concerning your visit of the Boulesse-Webshop may be transmitted to the third party provider. If you are at the same time logged on to your user account at that third party provider, your visit to the Boulesse-Webshop may be associated with your user account (e.g. Facebook profile) at that third party provider. Boulesse can neither influence the data transmission nor its content. For the purpose and scope of the collection of data and the processing and other use of data by your social media provider as well as your rights in this respect and your options for the protection of your privacy, please refer to the privacy policy of your third party provider.

7.3. Boulesse also uses Tawk.to for its live chat service. Tawk.to offers Boulesse employees an external platform for the management of chats. By using the chat you automatically use the services of Tawk.to and data is transmitted which is used for security and documentation. The collected data includes: chat history, name, contact data, IP address at the time of the chat and country of origin. These data are not passed on to third parties and are used only for customer communication and for internal statistics. By using the chat, you agree to this. Please find additional information from Tawk.to [here in their privacy policy](https://www.tawk.to/privacy-policy/).  

**8\. TRANSMISSION OF DATA TO SERVICE AGENTS**

8.1.   Beside the transfer of Collected Data within the analytical tools described in the section 6 and 7 Boulesse transmits certain Collected Data to service agents in Austria and abroad, which are instructed by Boulesse with the provision of certain services in connection with the purposes specified in section 5\. These service agents include the Boutiques and carriers, which require certain Collected Data (e.g. delivery address) for consignment and transport of the ordered goods to you. Furthermore, also banks and credit card institutions have to receive certain Collected Data for processing payments. By visiting the Boulesse-Webshop, you agree that Boulesse and its service agents process your Collected Data for the purposes specified in section 5.

8.2.   All data providers which are instructed by Boulesse according to section 8.1. undertake towards Boulesse to handle the received Collected Data in accordance with this privacy policy and the relevant data protection laws and to use them exclusively for rendering those services for which they have been instructed by Boulesse.

8.3.   Boulesse also uses additional external service agents to analyse the usage of the Boulesse-Webshop. By visiting the Boulesse-Webshop, you agree that these service agents collect anonymous data of a part of your visiting behaviour during your visit of the Boulesse-Webshop. The data collected in this way will be anonymously transmitted to servers of the service agents abroad, including in the United States. Boulesse only co-operates with service agents, which have contractually undertaken to Boulesse that they will not associate the anonymous usage data (which was collected in the way described above) with any other data which concerns you and which may have been collected on other websites. The identification by these service agents of visitors of the Boulesse-Webshop by their names is therefore excluded contractually and by technical means.  

**9\. TRANSMISSION OF DATA TO AUTHORITIES AND ILLEGAL ACTS**

9.1.   Boulesse and the Boutiques may be obliged to transmit certain Collected Data to customs authorities in order to complete customs declarations and other measures and declarations in the connection with the customs clearance of goods ordered by you in the Boulesse-Webshop.

9.2.   Boulesse will process any personal data beyond the scope of the Collected Data provided there is sufficient indication for such processing and as far as such processing is required in a particular case for the investigation and prevention of criminal offences, breach of contract and other illegal acts, in each case involving the Boulesse-Webshop. In order not to interfere with the investigation of such illegal acts, Boulesse will not inform the person whose personal data is processed.

9.3.   Boulesse may also be obliged by judicial or administrative requests in connection with Court or administrative investigations or with other suspicion of criminal or otherwise illegal acts to disclose personal data. Boulesse will comply with such requests provided they are in line with the laws. Again, in order not to interfere with the investigation of such illegal acts Boulesse will not inform the person whose personal data is processed.  

**10\. APPLICABLE LAW AND JURISDICTION**  

10.1.   This privacy policy is governed by the laws of the Republic of Austria excluding the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods (CISG).

10.2.   This choice of law is subject to mandatory consumer protection laws of the ordinary place of residence of any customer outside Austria, provided such customer has its ordinary place of residence in a member state of the European Economic Area (EEA).

10.3.   The relationship between Boulesse and customers who are consumers shall be subject to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of the Courts of the First District of Vienna. Claims by consumers against Boulesse based on mandatory consumer protection laws of the customer’s ordinary place of residence may be either brought before the Courts of the First District of Vienna or before the Courts of the EU member state where the customer has its ordinary place of residence.

10.4.   The relationship between Boulesse and customers who are entrepreneurs shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of competent Courts in commercial matters of the First District of Vienna. Furthermore, Boulesse is entitled to sue the entrepreneur at its place of general jurisdiction.  

**11\. GENERAL PROVISION**

11.1. In this privacy policy all references to individuals are neutral in gender and shall be interpreted equally in the female and male form

11.2. The ineffectiveness or unenforceability of one or more provisions of this privacy policy shall not affect the effectiveness or the enforceability of the other provisions of this privacy policy. Boulesse and the customer undertake to replace any ineffective and unenforceable provision by an effective and enforceable provision which fulfils the economic purpose of the ineffective and unenforceable provision as close as possible and which is effective and enforceable.

11.3. Boulesse reserves the right to amend this privacy policy at any time. The continued use of the Boulesse-Webshop is deemed to be your acceptance of all amendments of the privacy policy.
